Shadab Ansari

Bhopal / Mumbai / Bangalore ● +91 8369046737

EMAIL: shadab@geekpoint.net • GITHUB: github.com/shadab16

SKILLS

Proficient in TypeScript, JavaScript, PHP, HTML, CSS; and have a working knowledge of Java, SQL, C++, and Shell.

Developed with Angular, RxJS, NodeJS, jQuery, Symfony, Codelgniter; with focus on Functional Programming inspired by Haskell.

Familiar with haproxy, nginx, php-fpm, redis, and nodejs servers on GNU/Linux based systems (CentOS and Ubuntu). Worked with Jenkins, GoCD, Consul, Nexus, SonarQube, and Docker for developer operations.

Used Git and Subversion (SVN) for version control; with BitBucket and Gitlab for repository management.

EXPERIENCE

Product Development Manager, Zycus Infotech

2019 - now

Led strategy and implementation of handling legacy URLs and domains in new product suite's go-live. Led implementation of integrating new product suite with external SSO systems.

Improved CI/CD pipelines for product teams to have a single-click flow via Build, Test, Package, and Deploy to QA. Conducted multiple workshops for developers to upgrade front-end dependencies, build tools, and infrastructure software.

Created developer documentation website for improved DX (developer experience) and better visibility into releases & deployments.

Team Lead, Zycus Infotech

2016 - 2019

Led development for a product's front-end; including feature development, maintenance, and production on-calls. Improved cross-product API performance for specific business transactions.

Migrated engineering department's source code from SVN to Git; along with putting in place a formal code-review process and Jenkins DSL pipelines. Conducted training sessions with multiple product teams for Git migration.

Jointly led another team for developing new design system & common reusable Angular components used across the organization. Evangelized internal process of releasing org-wide libraries using SemVer.

Associate Technical Lead, Zycus Infotech

2015 - 2016

Improved product performance from an end-user's perspective (for page load and user interactions). Upgraded technical stack (nginx and php-fpm) for multiple products. Introduced peers to new development tools & best-practices for profiling JavaScript and PHP code performance.

Software Engineer, Zycus Infotech

2013 - 2015

Created product from scratch for supplier self-service. Created another minor product (integration with existing 3rd party product) for communication between suppliers and buyers. Performed code reviews for peers.

Freelance Web Developer

2007 - 2011

Built web applications ranging from simple HTML+CSS websites and content management systems to custom add-ons for vBulletin and XenForo based forum applications. Primarily used PHP and MySQL for the back-end.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

InstantEval

Ruby on Rails

Automated evaluation of programming tasks and assignments. Inspired by CodeChef, SPOJ, and ProjectEuler. For use in educational as well as competitive environments.

Scrabble-Helper

C++

Find all acceptable words when given a set of letters in the game of Scrabble. References J. Loughry. Efficiently Enumerating the Subsets of a Set. http://appliedmath.org/subset.pdf, 2000.

XF-Documentation

PHP, HTML, CSS

Developer-oriented documentation for XenForo: a proprietary but visible-source framework and forum software. Now defunct; available in internet archive: https://web.archive.org/web/20160908084644/tools.geekpoint.net/xfdoc/

XF-Redirect PHP, HTML, CSS

Generate custom Rewrite Rules for the Apache web server to prevent broken links for a vBulletin application. Now defunct; available in internet archive: https://web.archive.org/web/20110723053212/tools.geekpoint.net/xfseo/

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering, IT (RGPV), 2009 – 2013

CBSE – AISSCE, 2009 CBSE – AISSE, 2007

ACHIEVEMENTS

Awarded as the Super Star (Engineering) – 2019 in Zycus

Finalist in the TechGig CodeGladiators 2016 programming competition

Awarded as the Most Promising Performer (Engineering) – 2014 in Zycus

2nd position in CodingFingers 2012 programming competition

1st position in CodingFingers 2011 programming competition

Finalist in C Programming competition at Oriental College Techfest 2011